<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FEWD</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on FEWD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/objectives/</guid>
      <description> Understand how web pages are structured
 Introduce some of the most frequently used html tags
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/agenda/</guid>
      <description> HTML Structure
 Overview of basic HTML Tags
 Code Along (GA Press Release)
 Lab (Cookie Recipe)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Structure</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-structure/</guid>
      <description> Front page of a newspaper
 Which elements stand out and why?
 What would happen if every word was the same size font?
  Document in a word processor
HTML document
Summary  Structure helps readers better understand all forms of documents
 Documents leverage hierarchy, size and font weight to emphasize importance
 HTML pages are another type documents
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Tag Anatomy</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-tag-anatomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-tag-anatomy/</guid>
      <description>What is a Tag?  Tags act like containers, they tell the browser what type of information lies between (aka the content) the opening and closing tag
 Opening Tag
 comprised of character(s) surrounded by less than and equal than signs (brackets) characters within the brackets indicates the tags purpose  Closing Tag
 Same as opening tag except closing tag contains a forward slash which informs browser that element has ended   Terms “tags” and “elements” are often used interchangeably</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Attributes</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-attributes/</guid>
      <description>What is an HTML Attribute?  Attributes provide additional information about the contents of the an element.
 They are placed in the opening tag
 They have two parts: name, value
  Attribute Structure  Attribute Name
 Indicates what kind of extra information you are supplying to the browser about the content in the element characters within the brackets indicates the tags purpose  Attribute Value</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
      <link>/21-class-resources/keyboard-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/21-class-resources/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>General Window Management &amp;amp; Browser Shortcuts    Action Mac Windows     Open Chrome Developer Tools Cmd + Option + i F2 or Ctrl + Shift + i   Refresh page Cmd + R Ctrl + R   Switch between applications Cmd + Tab Alt + Tab   Switch between windows in the same application Cmd + ~     Atom Shortcuts Files, Windows, Tabs Management    Command macOS Windows Linux Description     Open File (Fuzzy) cmd-p or cmd-t ctrl-p or ctrl-t ctrl-p or ctrl-t Opens the Fuzzy Finder   Browse Open Files cmd-b ctrl-b ctrl-b Browse tabs within the window   Previous Tab alt-cmd-left ctrl-pageup ctrl-pageup Cycles left through open tabs (in the active pane)   Next Tab alt-cmd-right ctrl-pagedown ctrl-pagedown Cycles right through open tabs (in the active page)   Toggle Tree View cmd-k cmd-borcmd- ctrl-k ctrl-borctrl- ctrl-k ctrl-borctrl-| Toggles Atom&amp;rsquo;s file Tree View    Show Available Snippets alt-shift-s alt-shift-s alt-shift-s Shows the snippets available to Atom   Save cmd-s ctrl-s ctrl-s Saves the currently active file   Save As shift-cmd-s ctrl-shift-s ctrl-shift-s Saves the currently active file under a different name   Save All alt-cmd-s   Saves all changed files   Close Tab cmd-w ctrl-w ctrl-w Closes the currently active tab   Close Window shift-cmd-w ctrl-shift-w ctrl-shift-w Closes the currently active editor window   Split Window cmd-k up/down/left/right ctrl-k up/down/left/right ctrl-k up/down/left/right Split the currently active tab in one of the four directions   Focus Pane cmd-k cmd-up/down/left/right ctrl-k ctrl-up/down/left/right ctrl-k ctrl-up/down/left/right Move the focus to the pane in one of the four directions   Toggle full screen ctrl-cmd-f F11 F11 Toggle full screen window    Editing    Command macOS Windows Linux Description     Duplicate Lines shift-cmd-d ctrl-shift-d ctrl-shift-d Duplicates the line of the current cursor position and creates a new line under it with the same contents   Delete Line ctrl-shift-k ctrl-shift-k ctrl-shift-k Deletes the current line   Move Line Up ctrl-cmd-up ctrl-up ctrl-up Moves the contents of the current cursor position up one line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Files</title>
      <link>/course-materials/lesson-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:48:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-materials/lesson-files/</guid>
      <description>Lesson Files  Lesson 00 files (Course Intro &amp;amp; Tools) : No files needed
 Lesson 01 files (HTML Basics)
 Lesson 02 files (Git/Github): TBD
 Lesson 03 files (Relative Paths): TBD
 Lesson 04 files (Intro to CSS): TBD
 Lesson 05 files (CSS Selectors): TBD
 Lesson 06 files (CSS Box Model): TBD
 Lesson 07 files (Page Layout with Flexbox): TBD
 Lesson 08 files (CSS Positioning &amp;amp; Colors): TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body, Head &amp; Title</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/body-head-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/body-head-title/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;title&amp;gt; The following tags make up the structure of all web pages
 &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
 Represents the root (top-level element) of an HTML document, so it is also referred to as the root element
 All other elements must be descendants of this element.
  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
 Everything inside the body tag is shown inside the browser window  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
 Contains information about the page (vs shown on the pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/objectives/</guid>
      <description> Understand what the term &amp;ldquo;front-end Development&amp;rdquo; means
 Introduce tools you will be using throughout the class
 Cover class logistics, structure &amp;amp; keys to success
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Along</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/code-along/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/code-along/</guid>
      <description> Code Along: GA Press Release  As a class, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through using html to build out an html version of a press release
 Using Sublime, open the folder called ga_press_release (found within the starter_code) folder
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/lab/</guid>
      <description> Lab: Cookie Recipe  Work individually or in teams to create an html version of a Cookie recipe depicted in the images below
 Using Atom, open the folder called cookie_recipe in your lesson_01_files folder. You will be using these files as starting off point.
 Tips
 Focus on the content first, then the image then the CSS There will be some items that you will need to look up, CSS is one of them (don&amp;rsquo;t worry we will be going over this in the next class, but part of being a developer is being able to google your way to solutions)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solutions</title>
      <link>/course-materials/solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 14:08:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course-materials/solutions/</guid>
      <description> Solutions Disclaimer: These files are not meant to be viewed as the &amp;ldquo;right answer, instead view them as a way to learn how another developer approached the same problem.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/text/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/text/</guid>
      <description>HTML Headings  Six (6) levels of headings h1 tags is used for main headings h2 tags are used for subheadings Remaining level headings used as needed based on your content hierarchy  Browsers display headings differently, but relative sizes will always be consistent (by default) - i.e. h1 will always be bigger than h2
 JS Bin on jsbin.com
Paragraphs  Use &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; element to display paragraphs
 By default, browser displays each paragraph on a new line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is front-end Development?</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-frontend-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 19:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-frontend-development/</guid>
      <description>Overview  Front-end web development, also known as client-side development is the practice of producing HTML, CSS and JavaScript for a website or Web Application so that a user can see and interact with them directly.  What are the primary technologies associated with front-end development?  HTML
 CSS
 Javascript
  How is front-end development differ from back-end development?  Backend development, is also known as server-side development and involves storing data on behalf of users or customers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Logistics &amp; Materials</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-logistics-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:04:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-logistics-materials/</guid>
      <description>Class Logistics  Class Schedule: Monday &amp;amp; Wednesdays, 6:30pm - 9:30pm, from Mar 18th through May 22nd
 Break: 15 minute break during the middle of class from 7:45pm to 8:00pm (subject to change depending on flow of the class, but you&amp;rsquo;ll always get a 15 min break)
 Class Materials: Most lessons will include a set of files that you&amp;rsquo;ll work with during that lesson, we&amp;rsquo;ll refer to these files as the &amp;ldquo;lesson files&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/lists/</guid>
      <description>Lists  3 different types of lists:
 Unordered - lists start with a bullet point by default Ordered - numbered lists Definition - set of terms along with definition of those terms (not used often)  Both unordered and ordered lists contain list items
 list items elements are the items within list, they use opening and closing tag
 list item elements are indented by default
 list items elements are always a child a list element (in this case the “unordered list” or ul element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Tools</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:03:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</guid>
      <description>Text Editor:
 Why?: Text editor is a program that developers use to create and edit a range of programming language files. We&amp;rsquo;ll be using Atom, because it&amp;rsquo;s open source (free) and really good.
 Download Atom
  Browser:
 Why?: Google chrome is a robust browser with a variety of tools that are helpful to developers.
 Install Google Chrome
  Github:
 Why?: Github (and Git) are tools/applications used to by developers to manage their code and work collaboratively with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/links/</guid>
      <description> Links  Links created using the &amp;lt;a&amp;gt; tag
 link tags use the href attribute (remember attributes come with a name and a value)
 The value of the href attribute is the location where the link will direct you after it has been clicked
  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- contains information about the page --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;My page&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.cnn.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt; CNN &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/about_us.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;About Us&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folder Organization</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/folder-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:03:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/folder-structure/</guid>
      <description> Recommended Folder Organization  Create a folder in your Documents (My Documents on Windows) folder called FEWD
 At beginning of every class, download and unzip (mac instructions | windows instructions) the &amp;ldquo;Lesson Files&amp;rdquo; for that lesson directly into your FEWD folder
  While the lesson files will be hosted on Dropbox, you do not need to have a dropbox account to download the files.
  As the course progresses you&amp;rsquo;ll have a neatly organized listing of all of your work that looks similar to this:  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/images/</guid>
      <description>Images  Images are placed in a &amp;lt;img&amp;gt;
 Empty element meaning there is no closing tag
   &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;images/team_hands&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;a group of people touching hands in a star formation&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;teamwork is awesome&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  Image Attributes  src - Tells browser where to find the image (may relative or absolute path)
 alt - Provides description of image for people who cannot see the image (accessibility)
 title - Used to provide additional information about the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Success</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/keys-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 17:11:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/keys-to-success/</guid>
      <description>Do your homework: More you practice the concepts learned in class, the faster you&amp;rsquo;ll pick them up
 Don&amp;rsquo;t try to memorize anything: You&amp;rsquo;ll memorize things naturally through the act of doing things over and over again. Besides, if you don&amp;rsquo;t remember something just look it up (i.e. google).
 Work smarter not harder: In additional to looking things up, developers are really good at referencing past code that they&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to solve problems they encounter in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/tables/</guid>
      <description>Tables  Tables represent data in a grid format
 Table Tags
 &amp;lt;table&amp;gt;: element used to create a table
 &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;: table row
 &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;: table data, represents a cell in the table
 &amp;lt;th&amp;gt;: table headings used to respresent the header for a column or a row
   Learn more about tables here
 ---- Table examples  JS Bin on jsbin.com
JS Bin on jsbin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block &amp; Inline Elements</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/block-and-inline-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/block-and-inline-elements/</guid>
      <description>Block Elements  Block elements always appear on a new line in the browser window
 &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; are examples of block elements
  JS Bin on jsbin.com
Inline Elements  Inline elements will always appear to continue on the same line as their neighboring elements
 &amp;lt;a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;img&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; are examples of inline elements
  JS Bin on jsbin.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divs &amp; Spans</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/divs-spans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/divs-spans/</guid>
      <description>Divs  Divs allow you to group a set of elements together in one block-level box  JS Bin on jsbin.com
 Divs are mainly used to break your content up into logical sections. By doing so, you have more control of the layout and appearance of your pages.  Spans  Spans are the inline equivalent to Divs
 Spans are used to either:
 contain a section of text where there is no other suitable element to differentiate it from its surrounding text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Tags</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/other-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:29:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/other-tags/</guid>
      <description>Many more tags There are many other tags available to developers such as:
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt; Makes text bold&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i&amp;gt; Italic text &amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Used to break text within a paragraph &amp;lt;hr /&amp;gt; Used to add a horizontal line to visually break up text  JS Bin on jsbin.com
MDN (Mozilla Developer Network) is an excellent resource for all things HTML, CSS and Javascript. For a complete list of all tags avaiable click here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Assignment</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/reading-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 01:04:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/reading-assignment/</guid>
      <description>View the following videos before the next class
 Video: What is Version Control (6 mins) 
 Video: What is Git (8 mins)
 Video: What is Github? (4 mins)
  Complete the following tutorial before the next class
 Tutorial: Hello World Github Tutorial  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>